Guide to the DRIVE records, 1960-1991 IBT0070
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
DRIVE records
1960-1991
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT0070
1 document boxes Issues of DRIVE Reporter
DRIVE is the IBT's voter education arm. Launched in 1960 its purpose is to help elect candidates friendly to labor to public office. This collection consists of copies of the DRIVE Reporter, brochures, mailing materials, posters and other DRIVE promotional materials.
Arrangement
Collection: DRIVE records Organized into one series: DRIVE Reporter and DRIVE Special Edition
Arranged: DRIVE Special Edition is Folder 1, Folders 2-8 contain DRIVE Reporter in chronological order.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 2016 [2016.025].
Scope and Contents
This collection houses the regular and Special Edition volumes of the D.R.I.V.E. Reporter, special reports, DRIVE mailings and brochures and posters. Materials are dated from 1960 to 1991.
Historical Note
DRIVE - Democratic Republican Independent Voter Education - was officially launched by the IBT in 1960. Its purpose was and remains to elect candicates to public office who are friendly to the interests o Teamster members and to work for the passage or defeat of legislation of special concern to Teamsters.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Labor unions; Legislation; Politics and government; Labor; Labor negotiations
- D.R.I.V.E. 42 Special Edition & Booklet, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- D.R.I.V.E. Reporter: Vol.1, No.1-Vol.2, No.7, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- D.R.I.V.E. Reporter: Vol.3, No.1-13, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- D.R.I.V.E. Reporter: Vol.4, No.1-8, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- D.R.I.V.E. Reporter: Vol.5, No.1-18, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- D.R.I.V.E. Reporter: Vol.6, No.1-14, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- D.R.I.V.E. Reporter: Vol.7, No.1-7, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- D.R.I.V.E. Reporter: Vol.8, No.1-6, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Special Reports, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- DRIVE 1964 Activities (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Teamsters Congressional Action Grams, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Blank Documents and Sample Letters, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- DRIVE Brochures, ND (Box 1, Folder 13)
- DRIVE Posters, ND (Box 1, Folder 14)
- DRIVE Reporter Special Edition, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- DRIVE Teamster Recommendations: Democratic Platform Committee, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- DRIVE to survive pins (many), ND; IBT 0070 (Box Shared Box 31, Folder 4)
- Motor Carrier Safety Regulations Written Exam Published by DRIVE, January 1, 1971; IBT0070 (Box SHARED Box 31, Folder 12)
- DRIVE handbooks, 1981, 2015; IBT0070 (Box 1, Folder 17)